Glen Ellyn, Ill. Faith Congregational Church records, 1957-1992.
Congregational Library Archives
Glen Ellyn, Ill. Faith Congregational Church records, 1957-1992.
RG5241
Congregational Library Archives
0.79 Cubic Feet
(2 boxes)
Twenty-three miles west of Chicago there was an area known as Glen Ellyn Countryside (2.5 miles away from nearby Glen Ellyn). In 1956, several members of the community believed it was time to build a community church. By March of 1957, the tiny church had launched under the name "Countryside Community Church". Near the end of March, it was decided to hold services and Sunday School at the new addition of the Queen Bee School. Walter Ashley, one of the original community members trying to establish a church, would rely on help from the Congregational extension board to procure funds and ministers. In June of 1957 the by-laws were drawn up and the name of the church officially became "Faith Congregational Church". Reverend Ken Strokes would be hired as the first minister, moving to Glen Ellyn with his family. On November 2, 1958, the new chapel/parsonage was dedicated (although not completely finished). In 1961 and 1968, Faith Congregational Church saw its location expanded upon with two new buildings. The church continued to function through 1992, when it is believed to have closed down for good. This collection includes council meeting minutes, annual and project reports, by-laws, transfer letters, membership information and printed materials.
Faith Congregational Church (Glen Ellyn, Ill.)
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by the Chicago Theological Seminary in April 2014; Accession: 2014-88.
Custodial History
Items originally held by the Chicago Theological Seminary Library.
Historical Information
Twenty-three miles west of Chicago there was an area known as Glen Ellyn Countryside (2.5 miles away from nearby Glen Ellyn). In 1956, several members of the community believed it was time to build a community church. By March of 1957, the tiny church had launched under the name "Countryside Community Church". Near the end of March, it was decided to hold services and Sunday School at the new addition of the Queen Bee School. Walter Ashley, one of the original community members trying to establish a church, would rely on help from the Congregational extension board to procure funds and ministers. In June of 1957 the by-laws were drawn up and the name of the church officially became "Faith Congregational Church". Reverend Ken Strokes would be hired as the first minister, moving to Glen Ellyn with his family. On November 2, 1958, the new chapel/parsonage was dedicated (although not completely finished). In 1961 and 1968, Faith Congregational Church saw its location expanded upon with two new buildings. The church continued to function through 1992, when it is believed to have closed down for good.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes council meeting minutes, annual and project reports, by-laws, transfer letters, membership information and printed materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series and three subseries. Within each of these section the collection is further arranged chronologically.
Series 1: Church Records, 1957-1992.
Subseries 1: Council Meeting Minutes, 1969-1992.
Subseries 2: Annual and Project Reports, 1957-1992.
Subseries 3: Membership, 1957-1988.
Series 2: Printed Materials, 1957-1967, 1982.
Bibliography
Edmondson, Gloria. Faith Church, United Church of Christ, Our First 25 Years. Self-published. 1982.
Congregational churches -- Illinois -- Glen Ellyn.; Church records and registers.; Faith Congregational Church (Glen Ellyn, Ill.)
- Church records, 1957 1992; 1957-1992; 27 Items; (26 folders, 1 volumes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records of council meeting minutes, annual and project reports and membership information.
  - Council meeting minutes, 1969 1992; 1969-1992; 8 Items; (7 folders, 1 volume)
    This sub-series contains council meeting minutes for the Faith Church.
    - Council meeting minutes, 1969 1975; 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1971 1972; 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1976 1980; 1976-1980 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1980 1982; 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1983 1985; 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1986 1988; 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1988 1989; 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Council meeting minutes, 1990 1992; 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual and project reports, 1957 1992; 1957-1992; 7 Folders
    This sub-series contains annual reports and project reports such as the Loan and North Glen Ellyn.
    - North Glen Ellyn project, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Countryside Community Church project, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual reports, 1967 1973; 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Annual reports, 1975 1982; 1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Glen Ellyn loan, 1981 1986; 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Annual reports, 1983 1988; 1983-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Annual reports, 1989 1992; 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Membership, 1957 1988; 1957-1988; 12 Folders
    This sub-series contains records related to the membership of the Faith Church, including transfers, dismissions, by-laws and installations.
    - Transfers and dismissions, 1957 1962; 1957-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - By-Laws, 1957 1979; 1957-1964, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Calls for pastors, 1958 1963; 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters of dismission, 1960 1969; 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Installation paper, October 27, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Transfers and dismissions, 1963 1965; 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Received into membership, 1965 1966; April 1965-April 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Our Church Covenant, 1965 1992; 1965-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Transfers and dismissions, 1966 1968; 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Transfers and dismissions, 1969 1972; 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Transfers and dismissions, 1985 1988; 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Membership memorandum, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Printed materials, 1957 1982; 1957-1967, 1982; 3 Folders
  This series contains printed materials such as pamphlets, a history of the church and a newsletter.
  - Countryside Chatter, 1957 1957; 1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlets and handouts, 1957 1967; 1957-1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)